[SPEAKER_00] In the name of Allah, the Most Gracious, the Most Merciful. May Allah's peace, mercy, and blessings be upon you all. In the name of Allah, the Most Gracious, the Most Merciful. So, yesterday, we asked a question, a very, very good question, inshallah. He asked that, we know that ma is used for what? To ask about what? Yeah, something that has no intellect, right? As opposed to man, which is used to ask for something that? Has intellect, right? So, he asked that, in Surah Al-Kafirun, Allah told the Prophet ﷺ to say, وَلَا أَنْتُمْ عَابِنُونَ مَا أَعْبُثُ That you, meaning talking to the kuffar, you do not worship what I worship. The word ma is used, right? Now, who did the Prophet ﷺ worship? Allah, right? So, if he's talking about Allah, then why was the word ma used, right? So, it's a very good question, inshallah.
[SPEAKER_00] So, I had something in my mind about seeing when it comes to the Qur'an, especially the Tafsir of the Qur'an, it's the words of Allah ﷻ, Satan just did it based off a guess, right? Or based off your whims, right? Rather, it should be based on some sort of proof. So, that's why I didn't want to say anything out of the top of my head, so I went back and I checked out the Tafsir book, and it confirmed the idea I had in my mind, which is, there's a concept in Arabic called al-mushakala. This is when you get to the higher level. Right now, we're just learning basic, nahuwa and saraf, and basic Arabic, right? When you get to the higher level, it's something called balagha, which is rhetoric. Meaning, what is it that makes speech more beautiful? So, now, one concept in balagha, in Arabic rhetoric, is called al-mushakala al-abdiya. In terms of the way, because the Qur'an doesn't only consider the meaning, but it also considers the sound as well. This is why you see in many places, the Qur'an is rhyming, because that has a very powerful effect in the heart as well. So, in the same way, something that
[SPEAKER_00] affects the beauty of the speech is that, it is similar to what comes around it. So, the word maa was used before that as well. Basically, it becomes symmetrical, right? The same word is used multiple times. So, now, the word maa was used right before it, which is maa ta'abudun, laa abudhu maa ta'abudun, which is referring to the idols. The Prophet ﷺ was saying that, I don't worship what you worship, the thing that you worship, which is the idols. So, in that case, maa is justified. Why? Because maa is used for, things that don't have intellect, and idols obviously do not have intellect. So, using maa over there, it makes sense, and it's the way the rule normally goes. But in the context of Allah ﷻ, it's used out of its normal usage, for that purpose of symmetry, for keeping that symmetry. This is something that's, you know, it's a higher concept, but it's just an idea I wanted to explain to you, just to answer the question. But it's very good that you're thinking about that, and I want everybody to start thinking about that now. When you're reading the Qur'an, start applying these things. Wait, this is maa, okay, normally it's used like this, but why is it used in this context like this? Right,
[SPEAKER_00] there's a couple other things, right? One example, from the Qur'an as well, from maa, right? Allah ﷻ says, إِنَّكُمْ وَمَا تَعْبُدُونَ مِنْ ذُونِ اللَّهِ حَصَلْهُ جَهَنَّةً He's telling the mushrikun, that you and whatever you worship, will be the pebbles of hellfire. I mean, you will be burning in hellfire. So, the mushrikun, they thought, you know what, let's make a joke out of this. And they claim that, oh, we found a mistake, so-called, in the Qur'an, or a contradiction, so-called. They said, oh, you're saying that whatever we worship, is in hellfire, so some people worship Isa . So, are you saying that Isa is in the fire? He's a prophet of God, right? So, is he in the fire as well? So, you guys tell me, what does it enter to this question? What does it enter to this objection of the mushrikun, that thought they had a very good point, to the point where they're laughing, and Allah ﷻ actually talks about this in another ayah, He says, وَلَمَّا أَلْطُرِكَ أَبْنُ مَوْهِ عَنْ مَثَلًا إِذَا أَلْمُكَ مِنْ هُوْ يَسْلِبْ That they start laughing amongst themselves, when they give this example of Isa .
[SPEAKER_00] So, now you guys tell me, what's the answer to this objection? It's in Surah Al-Maal, and in Mark 15. We know that Isa says that, I'm not, you know, he's gonna say, I never told him, that's a question for you. Not exactly, but there's, that could be an answer, but this is, there's more of a straightforward answer. Ma is for things that don't have senses, and Isa . Very good, right? Ma is for things, that what? Do not have intellect. Isa , does he have intellect or not? Yes. Yes. So, a very simple answer, right? And this is an answer that Imam Al-Qurtubi mentioned, and an answer to this objection of the Mushrikun. Allah Himself answered that objection, but this is not the Seerah of the Dars, we won't go into details into that. But the point is, that you see, even the great Mufassirun, like Imam Al-Qurtubi, is using some basic things that we're learning here in Lesson 1, of Qurus Al-Lughat Al-Amabiya, which shows you how applicable what we're learning is. Right? Now, the question might come to our mind, oh, but wouldn't the Mushrikun know that? Right? They're Arabs, right? They knew Arabic much better than us,
[SPEAKER_00] we're just learning the first lesson of Qurus Al-Lughat, so how could they not know that? The answer is that, when people want to be stubborn, and they want to just stick with their own words, and they'll find any sort of justification, even if it makes no sense. And a great, you know, way to understand this is, just look at the Israelis. Look at the strange type of justifications they come up, and they know they're lying, and everybody who's listening to them knows they're lying. And you still have people who laugh it up and take it. Right? And that's the same way the Mushrikun, when they said this thing, their followers would just laugh it up and they would accept it. Right? So that's just the mindset we have to think of, when we think of these different things that, wait, that doesn't make sense, but you have to think about it from their perspective. They're trying to keep, they're trying to find any single thing they could to try to poke some sort of hole in the people's, in the Qur'an, or in the statements of the Prophet , even if it makes no sense. So yeah, so that's another example of math in the Qur'an, which tells us that we can, we can deduce these points just based on what we already know.
[SPEAKER_00] Okay. Now, part of the homework was to find that in the Qur'an. Right? So how many of us did that work? There was extra credit, it wasn't necessarily everybody didn't have to do it, but I encourage you to do these types of things so that we can exercise what we're learning. Okay. Very good. Mashallah. We almost did it. Alhamdulillah. You want to give an example? Yeah. This ayah in Surah Yaseen. Okay. Say it. On 36, ayah 36, Surah 36, ayah 48. BismillahirRahmanirRahim. وَيَقُولُونَ مَرْتَىٰ هٰذَا الْوَعْدُ إِن كُنْتُمْ صَادِقِينَ Okay. Very good. Mashallah. مَتَىٰ هٰذَا الْوَعْدُ إِن كُنْتُمْ صَادِقِينَ Right? The meaning of this ayah is, when is this promise if you are telling the truth? We're talking about what promise, right? The promise that the Prophet صلى الله عليه وسلم made, that the punishment is coming to them, the Day of Judgement is coming. Or that is a promise.
[SPEAKER_00] Right? So why was the word هَذَا يُوزْ Can anybody tell me why was the word هَذَا يُوزْ used over here? It's near, it's not far, it's singular, it's small. Okay. So over here it's not near in the physical sense, right? Because a promise is not something which is physical. But it's near in the sense that the Prophet صلى الله عليه وسلم was talking about it, he was constantly mentioning it. So saying this promise of yours that we keep on mentioning, when is it going to happen? So it's not near, that's something we have to keep in mind about هَذَا. We didn't mention it for near, but that nearness doesn't necessarily have to be physical nearness, it could also be understood in our context as well. So we got that? Good Mashallah, good example. Anybody else have something to add to it? So it might be, am I through the door? Okay. From هَذَا إِنْ أَنْتُمْ لَتَوْصِلُونَ Okay. Alright. أَفَسِرْتُمْ هَذَا إِنْ أَنْتُمْ لَتَوْصِلُونَ Yeah. أَنْتُمْ لَتَوْصِلُونَ Yeah. Very good Mashallah. أَفَسِرْتُمْ هَذَا So what was the ayah for that? فَقَوْفِهَا Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00] Just so I remember the context, what was هَذَا referring to? I think we were talking about جهنم. Yeah. We were talking about جهنم. Yeah. So Allah is telling these people that, you know, they used to joke around about جهنم and say that, you know, this is fake and stuff like that. So now Allah is telling them that is this magic now? هَذَا It's talking about this punishment. عَذَاب هَذَا So عَذَاب that word is male. It's something that is close to them because they're literally in the fire. Right? So is this fire, this punishment that you're in, is it, is this some sort of magic or something? Right? So that's the word هَذَا in that context. Very good Mashallah. I don't know if it's probably more than three but he mentioned it twice. هَذَا بَلَا بَلَا Okay. Very good Mashallah. We'll take a second example but it's easier because it's a physical thing. Right? So Ibrahim makes this du'a to Allah. What's the context of this du'a? The context is that he has left his son and
[SPEAKER_00] his wife where did he leave them? Desert. In the desert. Which desert? Makkah. Makkah, right? The valley of where Makkah currently is. That valley was completely desolate land. There's nothing there. So he left his son and his wife in that place and he makes this du'a He's having full trust in Allah because Allah is the one who told him to do that. So now he's just making dua from the bottom of his heart. He's saying, رَبِّ جَعَلْ هَذَا الْبَلَدَ آمِنًا O Allah, make this land peaceful. So now it's very obvious why he's saying this land, right? Can somebody tell me the three things? It is? Land, the word land is? Masculine. Masculine, male. Yeah, masculine. Then? Singular, good. And third thing? Nearby. Nearby, because he's literally in the land as he's making dua to Allah, indicating towards this land of Baqarah that Allah made this land a peaceful land. Everybody got it? Surah Al-Baqarah, Ayah 56. Okay.
[SPEAKER_00] هَذَا نُزِلُهُمْ يَوْمَ الدِّينِ Okay, very good, Mashallah. هَذَا نُزِلُهُمْ يَوْمَ الدِّينِ So before this, it talks about Jahannam, right? So I'm trying to find Jahannam in a lot of detail. فَشَارِبُوا الْعَلِيمِ الْحَمِيمِ فَشَارِبُوا الْشُرُوبَ الْبَلِّينِ هَذَا نُزِلُهُمْ يَوْمَ الدِّينِ Allah's indicating to that whole, you could say, passage that was mentioned before that, that's why it's mentioned هَذَا. Otherwise there are multiple things that are mentioned in it, but Allah mentions هَذَا as in the whole passage. Whatever was mentioned over there, it will be there, basically their outcome on the Day of Judgment, right? That's more or less what the ayah means, right? So it's referring to that which was mentioned right before this. You get it? سُرَةُ الدِّينِ آيَة 3 وَهَذَا الْبَلَدِ الْأَمِينِ Yeah. وَهَذَا الْبَلَدِ الْأَمِينِ Okay? So Allah's swearing by certain things, like the fig, the fig tree, the
[SPEAKER_00] olive tree, then. وَهَذَا الْبَلَدِ الْأَمِينِ And the mountain, then. وَهَذَا الْبَلَدِ الْأَمِينِ The mountain that Musa was spoken to by Allah . وَهَذَا الْبَلَدِ الْأَمِينِ And? Allah's swearing by this safe land, which is referring to which land? Makkah, right? That's the answer of the du'a I was talking about, because Allah did make that land safe. And so that's why it's called this safe land. هَذَا الْبَلَدِ الْأَمِينِ So, why would it be هَذَا? Because, is this surah a Makki surah, or not any surah? Anybody know? Makki surah? I'm pretty sure it's Makki surah. We can check it later, but it makes sense that it's a Makki surah, and that's why Allah's saying هَذَا, because they're literally in Makkah, and it's being revealed, so Allah's swearing by this land that they're in. Everybody understand that? Okay. We can take one or two more examples, and we can start today's lesson. Everybody find this beneficial? Yeah? It's drilling in the concept, right? So, I have two? Just one, because we don't have everybody's good hand.
[SPEAKER_00] Okay. وَمَا كَانَ هَذَا الْقُرْآنَ وَإِنْ يُفْتَرَى Okay, good. وَمَا كَانَ هَذَا الْقُرْآنَ وَإِنْ يُفْتَرَى Right? So, Allah's talking about this Qur'an. This Qur'an is being recited right before you, right? You're seeing it, people recite it, and it's also being written down right before you. This Qur'an would not be, your fill out needs to be, what's the word for it? To be invented, very good, mashaAllah. Right? This Qur'an is not such that it would be invented, right? So, it's referring to singular, it's a masculine word, and it's this Qur'an being recited before them, it's being written right in front of them, and not only the people who were first listening, but even us as well, right in front of us. Right? No, you wanted to speak? In the Surah, it's not in the verse, but it's قَالُوا يَوَلِنَا مَنْ بَعْتَ مِنْ مَعْبَدْنَا هَذَا مَنْ عَعْضَ مَعْضَ مَعْضَ مَعْضَ مَعْضَ Very good, mashaAllah. قَالُوا يَوَلِنَا مَنْ بَعْتَ مِنْ مَعْضَ مَعْضَ مَعْضَ هَذَا مَنْ عَعْضَ مَعْضَ مَعْضَ مَعْضَ هَذَا is referring to like this resurrection,
[SPEAKER_00] right? So this resurrection that they're experiencing. So because they're experiencing the resurrection, it's something which is close to them. It's happening to them, so it's as if it's close to them. As I said, هَذَا doesn't necessarily always have to mean something physically close, but it's something that has proximity to a person. So they're saying this resurrection is happening, هَذَا مَا وَعَضَ رَحْمَان This is what Allah SWT has commanded us. Everybody got that? Alright. What? Yeah, very good. That was another example that somebody, he mentioned also. He's from Surah Al-Yaseen though. It's the same as in Al-Quran. Yeah, in Al-Quran. So it's similar to the example that mentioned in the Quran. Okay, so the bottom line is, Salim had mentioned that yesterday we were doing a Tafsir of Surah Quraysh, and then the
[SPEAKER_00] ayah came up, فَلْيَعْبُدُوا رَبَّ هَذَا الْبَيْتِ So I explained there in some detail why is it that هَذَا الْبَيْتِ Because people of Marca, they were there, and they were listening to this, and Allah SWT was with Quraysh specifically. And Allah SWT said, you should worship the Lord of this house. Which house is it referring to? The Kaaba. Why is it هَذَا to them? Because they're in Marca, right? So it's literally right in front of you every single day. It's the center of your day-to-day life. So that's why it's هَذَا الْبَيْتِ. Everybody understand? So everybody now understand the concept of هَذَا? So we shouldn't make any mistakes on this, because we've seen so many examples from the Quran now. Got it? Okay. Now, who memorized the vocabulary? Okay, good. Let's put it to the test.
[SPEAKER_00] Okay, I don't know if my drawings are going to be the best for the animals especially, but we'll either try. Okay, let's just... I think I'll just Google a picture. It would be easier. What's this? Can you see it? This is the Quran. Okay, good.
[SPEAKER_00] مَا هَذَا Is it supposed to be مَا هَذَا or مَا هَذَا? مَا هَذَا Okay. So... And what's the answer? Somebody raise your hand if you want to answer the question. What does that mean? مَا هَذَا طَبِيبٌ Good. Good, mashaAllah. هَذَا طَبِيبٌ Okay. Okay. مَا هَذَا هَذَا نَجْمُن هَذَا نَجْمُن Good, mashaAllah. So... The simplest stuff I can draw.
[SPEAKER_00] مَا هَذَا مَا هَذَا هَذَا هَذَا هَذَا مَا هَذَا هَذَا هَذَا Mahatma, you see it? Oh, I don't see it, but I can see it. Good, okay. Mahatma.
[SPEAKER_00] All these Gen Z people don't know what Mendeel is. Why don't you write the word and then I'll read it to you. In English. In English. Why don't you write the word in English and then... Oh, am I drawing you that bad? No, no. No, no. No. No. Is this the box? It's the handkerchief. Mahatma. Hadadah, Himar. Mashallah, Reagan. Hopefully nobody called any of their siblings or their spouse or anything like that. I'm going to use this word. Oh, I have a question for the futsal. You better redeem yourself after last time. That was embarrassing. Where does this word come in the Qur'an? Talk
[SPEAKER_00] about the story of Uzair and how Allah put him to sleep for a hundred years and then he had his donkey with him and his food, etc. So Allah told him, look at your donkey. Any other example? I'll send you another example actually. In Al-Farah. Let somebody else do it. Come on, quick, quick, quick. Himar, Himar, come on. It could be a plural too if you want. Quick, just, I can think of three things right now. Oh. Very good, Mashallah. Somebody finish the ayah. Me, me, me, what did he say? He said, He said, He said, He said, He said, He said, Oh. Oh. He said right? Allah talked about the rabbis ofaufenit Israel that you know they were given a Doorat but they didn't take responsibility as they're supposed to and so He described Him as as a donkey who is holding Pipa ,
[SPEAKER_00] Understand? I mean to Tafseer of what that was that is not the point in the Qur'an. But encore la лقصة آه OK. And then the place of .. OK. OK. I think these graphs are pretty simple. Go to the root space. Go to the root space. Quickly. Deeper. Deeper. Deeper. Deeper. All right. Now we got the concept of habit, right? Then we also got the concept. OK. Let's just go a little bit more. How about ? All right. Do you ever understand the concept of ? Yes. All right. So you're asking, is this such and such? And if the answer is yes, then you say what? Naum. Naum. Naum. Naum. Naum. Naum. Naum. Naum. Naum. Naum. Naum. Naum. Naum.
[SPEAKER_00] Naum. Naum. We got this one, huh? Are you ready? I'm ready. Very outwardly. There you go. What is this? What is this? This is a star. This is a mosque. This is a house. This is a statue. This is a building. This is a heart. This is a body. Yeah, somebody tell me why. Right here. Whenever it's a
[SPEAKER_00] kesron, the wine is under on top still. The shabda, yeah. The shabda. Yeah. So it's wine under the what? The kesron. And if it's on top then? It's the rasgha. Oh, great. This is unlike the Indo-Pak script because it would be under the word, the letter itself, the word itself. But in the Arabic script, it's just under the shabda. So don't get confused because then a lot of people might just take it. But I would actually guess it. Do you know what this one is? Yeah. . Okay. All right. What is the one new thing that you learned in this lesson, your new thing you can do? What word? . Okay. very simply if you want to find it, it means that. The word that means that. but now I'm going to break it down what were the three things you said for hada or somebody remind me male
[SPEAKER_00] singular close now that you get is the same thing as hada in two things it's also for male and it's also for singular but it's different in one thing which is it's not close it's for things that are far you get it so that's the difference between hada and that it's the only difference otherwise they're both for things that are singular and both for things that are male everybody got that so you can add that to which family which is what type of family are they they're very judgmental they always communicate with other people so hada is part of the family but they're more focused on people who are far away not focusing on people that are close by they're focusing on people that are far away ok so the author is not always going to put and
[SPEAKER_00] as you learn more about Arabic I mean if you look at a normal Arabic book like a book that's written in Arabic besides the Quran and stuff they won't have any very few will have hada they won't have hada that's actually one of the most important things that we're learning we're going to learn soon inshallah is how to tell which letter it is and you'll be able to read if you open it up if you open it up it's just a full page of Arabic words without any vowels but you're expected to know exactly what that vowel is and masha'Allah you know I've literally seen there's a molessa in South Africa for the blind and I've seen them reading an entire page without any mistakes and they're reading it in braille without any podcast so if they can do it I can't believe them so so yeah okay so so that's simple right because legend
[SPEAKER_00] is far away star is far away how that messes with it okay one more thing we learned here besides the specific vocabulary but a general rule that we're learning I'll tell you do you want mine? no no Ali the Hamza right? yeah yeah but we learned that last time you're like it's just it's the same thing except you add it to the beginning of Dada Wa Wa very good right the word Wa Wa right this is a different family if you don't want to right it's a little early for this but so if you don't want to you don't have to write it down in our family as a new family but it's good to know right there's a family called Kuhufuna Kuhufuna
[SPEAKER_00] Kuhufuna Baqara But it's also known in blonde and green Arab He may be a muslim or but halal although Qaruf and Aqf are connecting letters. Just for you to get an idea of how to learn it now, other examples of Qaruf and Aqf is Faa, right? There's so many ayahs or words in the Quran that start with Faa, right? So Faa itself is a separate letter, right? فَبِمَا الرَّحْمَةِ مِنَ اللَّهِ إِنْ دَلَهُمْ فَبِئَيِّ آلَهُمْ That Faa is a connecting letter, right? So there's a difference between Faa and Wa, right? In terms of meaning and other things as well. So Faa is also, ثُمَّ is also a Qaruf, right? And there's a few others as well. So these are all connecting letters. So Wa is the most common, and very simply it
[SPEAKER_00] means? And. And, right? And. Everybody got it? It's simple when you translate it because everybody knows, if I were to explain the grammatical rules behind it, you would get a little confused, but if you just understand it, it means and. It's very simple, right? You're just adding something to another thing. You're stating one statement, which is and then you want to add something else, you say وَهَذَا وَذَٰدِكَ مَسْجِرٌ for example, right? So you're just adding something, right? So when you want to do that, you add Okay? So now you know a huge percent more of Qur'an because Wa is like a lot of different times comes with Qur'an, right? So mashallah. So that's something we learn. Your question? On page 10, وَ also comes in the first verse.
[SPEAKER_00] Good point. I didn't notice there was a very good observation, mashallah. I didn't realize there was a lot of points out there. So much to appreciate. At least somebody paid attention. I'm joking. Okay. All right. So we learned We don't need to learn any of the details. We'll just know for now that it means and. All right. وَهَذَا وَذَا كِسَانٌ وَذَٰدِكَ مَسْجِرٌ means horse. حِمَال means donkey. So the donkey is far away. So we think وَذَا لِكَ حِمَالٌ and the horse's co-sign says حَذَا Then وَذَا لِكَ حِمَالٌ لَا ذَٰلِكَ كِلْبٌ لَا ذَٰلِكَ كِلْبٌ So it's the same concept as أَهَذَا بْلَيْنك لَا هَذَا بْلَيْنك Get it? But except for something that's far. All right. So imagine there's a cat all the way back there. So I'm pointing at it and saying أَذَٰلِكَ كَلْبٌ What
[SPEAKER_00] would be the answer? لَا ذَٰلِكَ كِلْبٌ Mashallah. Very good. لَا ذَٰلِكَ كِلْبٌ All right. And then somebody's pointing at a bed. أَمَا ذَٰلِكَ Then you answer it. أَمَا ذَٰلِكَ كِلْبٌ So for example, let's say if I was I'm pretty close to this door. But let's say if I was far away from the door and I'm saying أَمَا ذَٰلِكَ What would your response be? أَمَا ذَٰلِكَ كَلْبٌ أَمَا ذَٰلِكَ كَلْبٌ أَمَا ذَٰلِكَ كَلْبٌ أَمَا ذَٰلِكَ كَلْبٌ أَمَا ذَٰلِكَ كَلْبٌ Very good, Mashallah. I mean, honestly if you want to be very technical with the grammatical terms I'm not so good with English grammatical terms so I don't know what it would correspond to in English but you can just try to connect the letters so the new family we're introduced to. Okay, then مَنْ هَذَا وَمَنْ ذَٰلِكَ
[SPEAKER_00] Let's say there's two people. One is right here مَنْ هَذَا وَمَنْ ذَٰلِكَ So let me ask you, Hussein مَنْ هَذَا وَمَنْ ذَٰلِكَ مَنْ هَذَا وَمَنْ ذَٰلِكَ وَمَنْ ذَٰلِكَ Right there, next to Basel. Where? Next to Basel, the right side. I've never heard of it. He's talking. He's talking. He's talking. Remember? Who remembers? No, somebody else should. I want to get everybody remembering everybody's names so we should know everybody's names in the class, Mashallah. Alright. ذَٰلِكَ سَطِيف Okay? Alright. Everybody's now scared that I will have to do the same again. Okay. مَنْ ذَٰلِكَ ذَٰلِكَ خَجَب ذَٰلِكَ ذَٰلِكَ By the way, nobody should feel bad if I call you out and don't feel like I'm just
[SPEAKER_00] singling you out or anything. We're just trying to keep things going. Oh, sorry, I skipped that. ذَٰلِكَ ذَٰلِكَ ذَٰلِكَ ذَٰلِكَ ذَٰلِكَ ذَٰلِكَ ذَٰلِكَ ذَٰلِكَ ذَٰلِكَ ذَٰلِكَ ذَٰلِكَ ذَٰلِكَ ذَٰلِكَ ذَٰلِكَ ذَٰلِكَ ذَٰلِكَ ذَٰلِكَ ذَّٰلِكَ ذَٰلِكَ ذَٰلِكَITH أَز不好意思 Ustad Abu Christil stress kita. What does it sound like? Sugar. That's what it really means. So we can say that sugar in the Arabic language. What is حجر? حجر is the... Oh, sorry. حجر is the stone. Do you know that? حجر is what? Yeah, like حجر is the stone. Very good. Mashallah.
[SPEAKER_00] The word حجر comes in the Quran many times. Can somebody tell me? Yeah, the plural of حجر. Okay, all right. That's good. حجر The fuel of حجر is men and stones. People and stones. May Allah protect us all. All right. سُكَرُ ذَلِكَ Laban. What is laban? Milk. Milk. Laban is milk. So we write that up. You don't know it. Where does laban come in the Quran? When Allah talks about the rivers of Jannah, Allah says وَأَنْهَارُ مِّنْ لَبَنِهِ There's four different rivers He mentions. Rivers of honey, pure honey, rivers of laban. وَأَنْهَارُ مِّنْ لَبَنِهِ
[SPEAKER_00] لَمَ يَدَغِيَ طَعْمُ Such milk that the taste has not changed. Because after a few days, milk is like, you can't even taste it. Today I tasted goat milk for tip tip. First time in life, I can't do it. So laban, such milk that the taste has not changed. It tastes amazing, right? So those are the other rivers of wine. Then, what was the fourth one? Honey. Honey. Water, right? Wine, honey, water. Yeah, yeah. Okay. Then, so that's laban. Laban also comes to other places. For example, Allah says, What is laban? What does laban mean then? Like the country? That's a good question. Lubnan, right? In Arabic, it's pronounced Lubnan. So I'm not sure what the exact etymology is. So, لَبَنَنْ خَالِصٌ سَائِقًا لِشَارِمٍ Right? وَمِنْ بَيْنِ فَلْتٍ
[SPEAKER_00] وَدَمٍ Allah talks about His amazing ayat, His amazing signs that point towards His greatness. So He talks about, between the, the filth, meaning the excretion, and the blood of the cow, Allah creates, لَبَنَنْ خَالِصٌ pure milk, which is tasty for those who drink it. I don't know how amazing the miracle is that, right? Where it's developed, in the stomach, you wouldn't even want to touch all that stuff. Yet, when it comes out, it's so pure and amazing, and so tasty, right? What an amazing sign of Allah . So Allah says, لَبَنَنْ سَائِقًا لِشَارِمٍ Right? Everybody got the vocabulary now? So let's just memorize that vocabulary. We have about 7-8 minutes. Why don't you, one, go over quickly, something with that. I'm going to tell you, part of your work will be, to find 5 places with that in the Quran, so we can practice. But one, one of the most obvious ones, is right at the beginning of the Quran. That you get kitab, where we were like, oh man, I took my example.
[SPEAKER_00] Right? So, that you get kitab. The question comes to mind here though, right? This is right at the beginning of the Quran. The Quran is right in front of us. You're reading the Quran. Right? Allah, doesn't it make more sense for us to say, had it been kitab without a fee? This is the book, in which there is no doubt. So why does Allah say, that you can kitab with something far away? Right? This is something that the scholars of Tafsir have discussed. There's multiple answers. That's the beautiful thing about the books of Tafsir, that scholars from throughout history, you know, different scholars will give you different answers, and all of them will be amazing, beautiful answers, to questions like this, right? A lot of times, you'll be reading the Quran, you'll think like, you know, why is it like this? And you'll think that you're the first one who came up with this question. But you don't know that literally hundreds of thousands of scholars have already discussed this point. They've had debates over this point. They've already come up with 15, 20 different answers about this exact point, that your question, when you think you're Einstein, you came up with the biggest question in the world. Right? So this question has been discussed since the early book of Tafsir
[SPEAKER_00] until now. Many of them have already talked about it. One of the most basic and simple answers, also beautiful answer, is, that it's as if Allah is saying, this book is of such a high status that you can imagine as if it's way above our heads in terms of status. Like it's such a high status. Right? And that's what some of them have mentioned. So when Allah says, what? Is that the same scenario? It could be, but it could be also referring to because, is, a day is not right now. Right? Allah is telling us that day is going to come. So in terms of time, it's as far, as far away. You get it? So it could be for that reason. I have a question. Does Laban mean yogurt or milk? Good question. So in classical Arabic, it meant milk. But now in today's global Arabic, Haleeb is used for milk more, and Laban is used for yogurt. Right?
[SPEAKER_00] That's a very good question. So, he said that, I'll explain right now that, Allah says, means day. Right? That is the day which is true. Right? So, I mentioned that is used because, the day of judgment is not now. It's going to happen after some time. So it's far away in that sense. Right? But he asked that in another ayah, is used for the very same day of judgment. This is the day of, of, in which it will be decided. It will be decided. Right? As they say, right? From the same root. Right? This is the day of. So, why did Allah say, have that here, and that over there? The answer is, in that surah, right? Right? So, it's the, the context is, Allah is describing the day of judgment, as if it's happening. You get it? So,
[SPEAKER_00] that's why Allah said, have that. This is the day that's happening, right in front of you. Even the previous examples, today, some people gave examples, of that, that were from the day of judgment. Right? So, in, , , right? One of those mentioned it. So, that was because, they're in the day, Allah's describing it, as if they're already in the day of judgment, and that's what they're gonna say. Everyone understand that? So, so, what, is there, is there a distinction, when somebody uses, and, when, when in the Qur'an, he's describing, what's going to be on that day, and whenever, so, but it's not happening yet. Yeah. When we use it, it's already happening. It's already, meaning, oh, and that's in the future time. Well, yeah, when we use it, in normal speaking Arabic, Yeah. it's happened, or it's going, it's, it's happened, or it's happening, but when the, when the Qur'an is being used, it's in the context that, it's being talked about, as if it's happening. It depends on the context. Sometimes it's talking about, as if it hasn't
[SPEAKER_00] happened yet, and sometimes it's being talked about, as if it's going to happen. Do you get it? Or, or it is happening now. Right? So, it's not, it's not a one-size-fits-all rule. Sometimes the Qur'an is used in that context, sometimes it's used in the other way. Right? So, hopefully these examples, I'm going to keep on bringing the Qur'an in, because, that's all the purpose, right? To understand it, through the Qur'an. So, the more examples we use, the more we'll understand, and the more we'll understand, how deep the Qur'an is, and how, even with these basic things, we'll understand, and appreciate the Qur'an much more. Does everybody like that, or do you want me to just stick to the book? No, no, no. Just stick to the book? No, no, no. Just stick to the Qur'an. Alright. Inshallah. What else? I was going to go into the next lesson, but, I mean, it's only a couple minutes, so there's no point in going into the next lesson. Inshallah. So, the next lesson, what I'm going to do is, I'm going to send, who here is not on the WhatsApp group yet? Who has not added to the WhatsApp group? Okay. Brother, can, can, can you get their numbers? Raise your hand, please. Please see Brother
[SPEAKER_00] Mustafa. If you haven't, they don't add it to the WhatsApp group. After the class, Inshallah, he will have you add it to the WhatsApp group. It's important to be on the WhatsApp group, because, I'm going to be mentioning important updates, or, for example, tomorrow, for this upcoming lesson on Monday, I'm going to be mentioning, I'm going to be telling you guys to read, a certain lesson, from another book, not from this book, but from a different book, and, Inshallah, we'll discuss that in the next class. But I want you to read it, so that you have an idea of what we're going to talk about. Inshallah. Otherwise, I'll just bring it up right away. Now we're going to go into a little bit of grammar, right? So don't get confused, but, so I want you guys to read it beforehand, so that you have an idea. Inshallah. So, please check the WhatsApp group, in about a day or two, I will have it up. Inshallah. So please read the lesson. So part of the homework is, read what I'm going to, give you, in the WhatsApp group. Then, find five examples, or if you want to go, even further, find ten examples, for your own benefit, and look at a translation of those, of that Iqa. So, then, I can't say five examples of what, because there's
[SPEAKER_00] like countless in the plan, right? Then besides that, the homework, let's see, Tamrin, then just do the Tamrin as well, right? The Tamrin is, the, this, practice, the exercise, just do that. Read, write, and also translate. A lot of your brothers, they either, or either they translated, or, they wrote it down. So I want you to do both, write down the Arabic, and translate it. So that's how each will be beneficial for you, if you can do both. And, and also, get some practice writing. Also, if anybody didn't see the, in the WhatsApp group, we had mentioned that, there is a book, that I recommend, I have the book at home. It's a very nice book. If anyone wants to see it, actually, I can show them now. I can bring it from home, if anybody is interested in seeing the book, before they commit to buying it. There's a book, that's very good for practicing writing, and it's self-explanatory. You don't need me to sit and say, okay, do this, It explains it in the book as well. But it explains how you write the word, when it's the beginning
[SPEAKER_00] of a word. The letter, when it's the beginning of a word. How the letter looks, when it's the middle of a word. How it looks at the end of a word. It helps you practice all of that. So it's a very nice book. It's a very systematic book. It's about, I think, $14. So, whoever wants to order it, it's not part of the course, but, anybody wants to practice their writing, so they can improve their Arabic writing, handwriting, then, they can order that book. I mentioned that, if one wants the book, they can like it, and then, one of the brothers who's interested, they can volunteer, they can purchase it with their car, or something, and everybody can pay in cash, or Zelle, or whatever, whatever you guys decide on. So, does anybody want to see the book, before purchasing? Okay, so I'll bring it from home right now, inshallah. Anybody else, anybody else wants to see the next one? I can volunteer money, so I'm sure. Okay. So, Brother Shahnawas volunteered to pay for it, so everybody can just pay him. Please make sure, sometimes it happens, where brothers, they say, okay, buy one for me, and they don't end up showing up, they don't take it, so please, you know, everybody, inshallah, make sure you pay the brother for it. Okay, so yeah, but if you saw
[SPEAKER_00] the group, I just mentioned, because easier like that, we'll just count the number of people, who liked my message, and that will make it easier, for us to count, how many people, how many copies we need. So, just check the group, I posted, if you want the book, then just like this message, just give it a like, on the website, inshallah. So, that's the homework. Five examples, or ten examples of Zadik, or whatever you want, the more the better. and memorize the new vocabulary, it's not much. Can you recap on the lesson? Can you just have a recap? Recap on the lesson? The rule of Zadika? Sure, yeah. So, what's the rule of Zadika? Singular. Somebody tell me. Singular. Masculine. Masculine. And? Farwa. Farwa. Whereas, Hatha is? Singular. First, singular masculine, then we just close five. Okay? Singular masculine. For Zadika? Singular masculine. No, no. Very good question. So, don't get confused, right? For Hatha, we talked about something which has,
[SPEAKER_00] shh, guys stop talking. For something that has Hatha, intellect or no intellect, right? That's only for Ma and Man. Right? We don't care about intellect or no intellect, when it comes to Hatha and Zadika. Right? Hatha can be used for something with intellect, or without intellect. Right? It's just used for indication for anything. Right? Same thing with Zadika. Zadika can be used for something with intellect, or without intellect. Like an object, an animal, or human being. It can be used for any of those things. So don't get that mixed up in mind. So, the intellect and no intellect only applies to what? Ma and Man. Ma and Man. So which one is for intellect? Man. Man. And no intellect? Man. Man. Okay, good. Oh yeah, so we learned Man, right? So, find five examples of Man, as well. This is optional homework, because it might take some time. The Zadika one, Man, is optional homework for those who want to go above and beyond. But the bare minimum everybody should do is to Tamreen over here and memorize the vocabulary. Okay? We
[SPEAKER_00] might have a, we might have a pop quiz for vocabulary soon, insha'Allah. So make sure you know all the vocabulary, insha'Allah. Here. For Tamreen and Ma, it just says Al-Kalimaat Al-Jadida. Oh yeah, sorry. So, Al-Kalimaat Al-Jadida. Al-Kalimaat means word. Al-Kalimaat is a plural. So, word, Jadid means new. So, Al-Jadida is used, is feminine. We'll learn the rule for that later why it's feminine. But, so, Al-Kalimaat Al-Jadida means new words. So, this actually made it easier for you. You don't have to go through the whole lesson and see, okay, which are the words we didn't learn so far. You just list them all in one little box here. These are the new words that came up in this lesson. So, you just need to memorize these four words if you've already memorized the previous words. Got it? So, this is not a Tamreen. So, you said that we can, we'll be able to use it for Tafsir or
[SPEAKER_00] Tafsir, that will come inshallah along with some time. Right now, we're a little bit, it's a little early for us to get to Tafsir. But, after some time we'll get there. I just want to go back to the example you gave that when you asked that I'm standing here and my mom is standing over there. So, what, how do you say it in Arabic? . What's that again? . I just gave that example to you because that was the exact word used in the book. But, is used for the class, right? No, that's is a class. is a teacher. is a school building. Right? So, it's a school, you get it? So, I just mentioned that last lesson just to keep, for us to keep in mind that when you have the same root letters, there's a connection and correlation to the meaning. We'll learn the details of that later on, but that's something to just keep in mind for now. Sure. Do you want to focus in front of us? Is there a reason why
[SPEAKER_00] you want to focus the Adlerian part before the English? Is there a hiccup behind it? I mentioned in the first lesson, too, is there a reason why we're starting from this Arabic part and we're not going to why aren't we using the translation? I mentioned in the first lesson that I don't like using this translation, that's why I recommend if you want, just take this part, we're not using it at all, because I prefer learning Arabic through Arabic, right? If you have a translation and you just use it as a crutch, you don't actually learn anything, you don't actually remember anything. If you just use only the Arabic part, which we're going to be doing, then you're forced to remember it. Everybody get that? That's why we're not using that part at all. That's the reason why we're using it. Alright, Joe, you can end the class now. You can be late.